Abraham Velazquez

MECHATRONIC ENGINEER

Celphone: (+1) 365 476 8048

Email: luisabraham.velazquez21@gmail.com Address: 71 Frederick Tisdale, Toronto,ON

Age: 26



Young innovator with leadership and problem-solving skills, dynamic and responsible with experience and project execution. I seek to develop professionally within the best companies, to begin contributing capital and human value to highly prestigious companies.

EXPERIENCE

Applications Engineer | G3 Ingenieria

May 2021- Jan 2022

- Planned and completed group projects, working smoothly with others.
- Worked with cross-functional teams to achieve goals.
- Identified needs of customers promptly and efficiently.
- Exceeded customer satisfaction by finding creative solutions to problems.

Electronics Technician | TE Connectivity Automotive

Jan 2021- May 2021

- Support to production lines and integration of new improvements to increase the productivity of production lines, provide new designs, Automation, etc.
- (PLC, Mechanical Drawing, Sensors, vision camera, Laser marking machines, Welders, Presses, Electrical Tests, Leak Tests, etc.), Modification and development of programs in LabVIEW to optimize, improve and prioritize the safety of our clients' products.

Manufacturing Technician | TE Connectivity Automotive

Oct 2019- Jan 2021

- Analyze, propose and develop engineering works (Design of new improvement prototypes, KAIZEN,
 Time Reduction, Continuous Improvement) and in the area of mechanical design (Aluminum parts,
 stainless steel, fixtures, guards, supports, etc.) to optimize and improve processes in the
 manufacturing industry
- Preventive and corrective maintenance of critical equipment, as well as integration and implementation of improvements in them (PLC, Vision System, Enabling of new Sensors, Innovation, etc.).

Manufacturing Engineering Intern | TE Connectivity

Sep 2019- Oct 2019

- Documentation of new projects and equipment, support for lines in launch
- SolidWorks Design of Fixtures for 3D Printing
- Layout Design in AutoCAD
- Installation of equipment and design of structures
- Application of improvement techniques on critical equipment (Run and rate, etc.).

SKILLS

- PLC programming Allen Bradley, Siemens, Omron, Delta. Knowledge of CCW, Tia Portal, ISPsoft,
 DopSoft, etc. programming software(intermediate level).
- Knowledge of Ethernet/IP, rs232, profinet, rs 485 and modbus communication protocols. HMI (Human Machine Interface) Programming Allen Bradley, Siemens, Delta(intermediate level).
- Project planning and execution.
- Knowledge of security system, security interlocks, etc.
- Knowledge of COGNEX and KEYENCE vision systems.
- Programming in LabVIEW.
- Java NetBeans Programming, HTML, JS, React, Node,..
- Interpretation of electrical control diagrams.
- Knowledge about manufacturing processes.
- Knowledge of mechanics.

- Advanced Mechanical Design in SolidWorks (Finite Element Method, Design of Fixtures, Assemblies, Structures, Sheet Metal, etc.)
- Design AutoCAD.
- Mechanical Design at Spaceclaim.
- Knowledge of pneumatic valves, actuators, etc.
- Experience in assembling control cabinets, assemblies,
- Knowledge of geometric tolerances.
- Handling tools, wrenches, screwdrivers, drills, grinders, etc.
- Management of Conventional and CNC Milling Machine.
 G and M language.
- Basic programming in Mastercam.
- Management of computer software Microsoft Office Package, (Microsoft Word, Excel, Etc).
- KAISEN.

EDUCATION & TRAINING

University of Sonora, MX - Hermosillo, Mexico | Bachelor of Science

Mechatronic Systems Engineering, 12/2019

Cornerstone Community College - Vancouver, BC | Associate of Science

Web And Mobile App Design And Development, 01/2024

Additional Training Certifications

- Festo automation equipment training course, 07-Sep-2017 Universidad De Sonora.
- SolidWorks Design Course June to July 2019
- CNC Course January to February 2019
- In-Sight EasyBuilder and Spreadsheet Standard Course November 2020, Cognex
- LabVIEW Associate Developer (Certified).
- Lean Manufacturing January to February 2021 (Certified).
- Lean Six Sigma White Belt.
- Lean Six Sigma Green Belt.
- Machine learning and industry 4.0. May 14, 2021 (certified).

APTITUDES

- Proactive
- Autodidact
- Interest in learning.
- Problem resolution.
- Criterion and Analysis.
- Responsible and committed.
- I work under pressure.

- Schedule availability.
- Availability to travel.
- Fast learning.
- Negotiation.
- Team leadership.
- Customer service.

LANGUAGES

English - C1 Advanced

Portuguese - Intermediate

Spanish - Native/Bilingual

ADDITIONAL INFO

Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/luis-abraham-velazquez-angulo-73a8ab1a6/ **GitHub**: https://github.com/Programer1997

VISA US

Car

G full licence